<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on masontuckett.xyz</title>
    <link>https://masontuckett.xyz/tags/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on masontuckett.xyz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>mason@tuckett.xyz (Mason Tuckett)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>mason@tuckett.xyz (Mason Tuckett)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Copyright ©2025 Mason Tuckett All Rights Reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 00:38:44 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://masontuckett.xyz/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Career Update</title>
      <link>https://masontuckett.xyz/posts/career-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 00:38:44 -0700</pubDate><author>mason@tuckett.xyz (Mason Tuckett)</author>
      <guid>https://masontuckett.xyz/posts/career-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Personal Update on My Transition to Education&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-need-for-clarification&#34;&gt;A Need for Clarification&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In my personal life, I have received a lot of confusion and outright bewilderment as to why I am choosing to &lt;em&gt;temporarily&lt;/em&gt; transition into secondary education.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I am relatively public, and this website serves as a sort of refined &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;proof of character&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;—I wanted to dispel the misconceptions and vast mischaracterizations levied against my trajectory.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;WHY!?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To outsiders, it appears as if I am throwing away a fledgling, long-term career in cybersecurity; &lt;strong&gt;that is objectively the furthest thing from the truth.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Personal Update on My Transition to Education</p>
<h2 id="a-need-for-clarification">A Need for Clarification</h2>
<p>In my personal life, I have received a lot of confusion and outright bewilderment as to why I am choosing to <em>temporarily</em> transition into secondary education.</p>
<p>As I am relatively public, and this website serves as a sort of refined <em><strong>proof of character</strong></em>—I wanted to dispel the misconceptions and vast mischaracterizations levied against my trajectory.</p>
<h2 id="why">&ldquo;WHY!?&rdquo;</h2>
<p>To outsiders, it appears as if I am throwing away a fledgling, long-term career in cybersecurity; <strong>that is objectively the furthest thing from the truth.</strong></p>
<p>I had tried for years to enter the cybersecurity market during my time at Weber State University—<strong><em>all to no avail</em></strong>.</p>
<p>Suddenly, my efforts started to rapidly catch up to me, and everything changed once I concluded undergrad.</p>
<p>A slew of job offers, significant recruiter outreach, and several tenured professionals offering referrals—<strong><em>all at once</em></strong>.</p>
<p><strong><em>What changed?</em></strong></p>
<small><i><b>Absolutely nothing—merely a piece of paper adorning my wall.</b></i></small>

<p>Consequently, this left me in a state of immense disarray, absolutely appalled—culminating in an arduous, nearly two-month-long period of intense introspection.</p>
<h2 id="what-i-realized">What I Realized</h2>
<p>I intrinsically, fundamentally disagree with cybersecurity&rsquo;s current state of rampant credentialism, egoism, nepotism, and overt gatekeeping.</p>
<p>As a person of such impressive credentials (<em><strong>given my age</strong></em>), I never found myself claiming <em>SME-level expertise</em>.</p>
<small><i><b>Why must this be such a pervasive issue?</b></i></small>

<p><strong>I had witnessed this firsthand:</strong> plagiarized presentations, falsified credentials, glorifying aims to work for highly unethical corporations, and extreme embellishment to the point of outright deceit.</p>
<small><i><b>But it never really "clicked" until just recently.</b></i></small>

<p><em>I was faced with an existential, spiritual rot—of which I want no part of.</em></p>
<h2 id="my-journey">My Journey</h2>
<p>I am not some <em>&ldquo;prodigy&rdquo;</em> or <em>&ldquo;gifted individual&rdquo;—I am a man who had to earn and fight <strong>tooth and nail</strong> for everything I have ever achieved.</em></p>
<p>I entered college with zero plans or in-depth understanding of technology; <em>I was quite infantile, toying with computers as a hobby.</em></p>
<p><strong>The only reason I even pursued higher education was because I was given a life-defining ultimatum:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The Air Force</li>
<li>Vocational School</li>
<li>Homelessness</li>
</ul>
<p>I was nearly a <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20251026111432/https://prezi.com/p/pdoo8ktodsxb/booth-and-hamlet-justifications/">high school drop-out</a> at age sixteen—migrating to online education—<em>in hopes of recovering what little I had left.</em></p>
<p>Even at that moment, I still chose not to do critical homework, contingent upon my graduation, for nearly two years—<em>up until age eighteen.</em></p>
<small><i><b>Abysmal ACT scores and a nonexistent GPA.</b></i></small>

<p>So you may understand just how discouraged I was—<em>having to construct everything from scratch</em>—<strong><em>by hand</em></strong>.</p>
<small><i><b>Without the educational scaffolding or innocence many children hold during childhood.</b></i></small>

<p>In the years to come, as I received a highly sudden yet continuous flow of praise—<em>I was left stewing, questioning:</em></p>
<p><strong>What Now?</strong></p>
<h2 id="service-as-a-career">Service as a Career</h2>
<p>I harkened back to my time as an instructor at Ken Garff&rsquo;s summer tech track—and the countless hours I spent debugging with <a href="https://smithbarlow.net">Smith</a>.</p>
<small><i><b>I realized in that moment that my life should be for and in the service of others.</b></i></small>

<p>I declined lucrative offers, and opportunities, and referrals, and set my sights on pursuing teaching licensure—with an excruciating fervor.</p>
<small><i><b>A sharp juxtaposition to my idea of education as a cheap contingency option.</b></i></small>

<p>To build myself from the ground up, I took a TA position at a local elementary school—<em>with <strong>zero</strong> understanding of what I&rsquo;d be doing.</em></p>
<p>Entering the role was among the most difficult adjustments I had made in my career.</p>
<p><strong>Far surpassing any academic work or position I have ever held.</strong></p>
<p>It has been the most rewarding experience of my life—<em>providing a level of happiness I have never known.</em></p>
<h2 id="the-future">The Future</h2>
<p>While I am focusing on adjunct roles at technical colleges in the near future, secondary education gives me an incredible platform.</p>
<p>I am uniquely positioned—attaining invaluable experience while having plenty of time for PhD coursework.</p>
<p>Additionally, I will absolutely continue my contracted network engineering projects—<em>compounding into my aim to do technical consulting.</em></p>
<small><i><b>I am not "ditching" my technical background, but strategically adapting to preemptively advance beyond my years.</b></i></small>

<p>Professorship is my end goal—<em>building a profile for mentoring <strong>lost men in a sea of disillusionment and demoralization</strong></em>.</p>
<p>Hence my desire to become involved with the youth—<em>hopefully, in due time,</em> <em><strong>piloting initiatives to ensure children receive the scaffolding I never had</strong></em>.</p>
<h2 id="the-present-game-plan">The Present (Game Plan)</h2>
<ul>
<li><em>Continue volunteer work.</em></li>
<li><em>Continue mentoring Smith.</em></li>
<li><em>Finish my catalog of technical articles.</em></li>
<li><em>Earn <a href="https://github.com/masontuckett/pcap-prep">PCAP</a>/<a href="https://github.com/masontuckett/cpe-prep">CPE</a> certs so I may better teach students.</em></li>
<li><em>Earn CCNA/RHCSA for adjunct roles.</em></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
